

Nino Sauli

Nationality: Albanian Date of birth: 14/11/1996 Gender: Male

Companies Companies Comp

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nino-sauli-380372174/

• Home: Rruga Sheshi Jozef Shtraus, 1015 Tirane (Albania)

ABOUT ME

I'm Nino, a frontend developer with a Bachelor's degree focused in Informatics from Universiteti i Tiranës. In the last year I have acquired valuable experiences and knowledge. My goals are to become an expert in frontend and technologies related. This means not only understand the basics, but also keep up with the latest progress and best practices in the development ecosystem.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer

ICT Group SRL [01/04/2024 – Current]

City: Reggio Emilia | Country: Italy

- Created, Developed and maintained responsive mobile applications using React Native CLI and EXPO, JavaScript, and TypeScript.
- Created Webpack config files to run the react native cli project on the browser.
- Worked with environment variables and prebuild files to configure the project with npm commands on build.
- · Android Manifest for different accesses.
- Used both android studio and physical mobile for development.
- Utilized Navigation for routing and navigation
- Worked with Async Storage for offline application usage.
- Utilized React Native Hooks and Recoil for efficient state management.
- Integrated RESTful APIs to fetch and manipulate data from backend services.
- Designed and implemented UI components using Nativewind CSS, Stylesheets, React Native Paper, React Native Vector Icons.
- Conducted API testing using tools like Swagger and Postman.
- Worked with third party libraries like Vision Camera for reading QR code/Barcode, Signature Canvas for using digital signature React Native FS for crud operations on files.
- Proficient in version control using Git and GitHub for source code management.
- Collaborated closely with backend developers to implement best practices and resolve issues.
- Worked with teams on remote, ensuring effective communication and collaboration.

Industries: Healthcare

Frontend Developer

ChWeb [01/08/2023 - 20/03/2024]

City: Tirane | Country: Albania

- Developed and maintained responsive web applications using React, Vite, Next, JavaScript and TypeScript.
- React hooks, Context API, and Redux for state management.
- Worked with RESTful API integrations to fetch and manipulate data.
- Designed and implemented UI components using CSS, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Shadon, Radix UI, and Metropic
- Implemented CRUD operations in tables to manage data effectively.
- Implemented client side and server side multifilters for data filtering, sorting and pagination.
- Utilized React Router for routing and navigation.
- Worked with third party libraries like axios for data fetching or formik and zod for input validation.
- Worked with Swagger and Postman for API testing.

- Proficient in version control using Git and GitHub for source code management.
- Familiar with Azure DevOps for agile management.
- Collaborated closely with backend developers to implement best practices and resolve issues.
- Worked with teams on-site and remote.

Industries: Booking, CRM, financial, e-commerce

Frontend Developer Intern

ChWeb [01/04/2023 - 31/07/2023]

City: Tirane | Country: Albania

- Built UI by creating and using various react components, ensuring that the content and layout fit together, perfectly to different screen sizes and devices using TailwindCSS.
- I created and optimized the React components, making them reusable and efficient to improve performance overall of the application.
- Worked with all the shadcnUI components.
- Used prop drilling to pass information between components.
- Worked with different hooks to add state and other features to functional components
- By working as part of a team, I learned the importance collaboration and communication effective in achieving the project objectives.

App Data Entry Specialist

We Are Fiber [01/06/2020 - 31/03/2023]

City: Tirana | Country: Albania

- Collecting and digitizing data.
- Maintaining a detailed and organized file system to ensure data entries are complete and accurate.
- Addressing data inconsistencies by working with administrative staff to locate missing data.
- Attending to data queries and reporting any major data errors to management.
- Adhering to best data management practices and maintaining a high standard of accuracy and efficiency.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor's Degree, Informatics

Universiteti i Tiranes [09/2015 – 06/2018]

Database; Statistics; C++; HTML; CSS; JavaScript; PHP; Java; Network; Foreign Language (English); General and Applied Mathematics;

High School Certificate

Janaq Kilica - Public high school [09/2012 - 06/2015]

City: Fier | Country: Albania

Literature; History; Geography; Foreign Language (English and French); Mathematics; Physics; Chemistry; Biology; Technology;

COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS

The Complete SQL Bootcamp 2022: Go from Zero to Hero

Udemy Online Courses

Working with PostgreSQL; SQL statement; Group by statement; Joins; Advanced SQL commands; Aggregate functions; Creating databases and tables;

Issued Aug 2022 · No Expiration Date

Credential ID UC-fbee4685-fb44-4793-b5f7-949e60d3d3e5

Link: https://www.udemv.com/certificate/UC-fbee4685-fb44-4793-b5f7-949e60d3d3e5/

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Albanian

Other language(s):

Italian English

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1 LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1 SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Frontend Development (HTML; CSS; Javascript) / Html Css Bootstrap / PostgreSQL - Basic / MS exel

ORGANISATIONAL SKILLS

Organisational skills

- Leadership
- · Good organisational skills
- Team-work skills

COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Communication and interpersonal skills Good communication skills gained through my experience as retention agent including :

- Negotiating
- Mentoring
- Teamwork
- Active listening
- · Open-Mindedness

JOB-RELATED SKILLS

Job-related skills

- Proficient in MS Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Outlook,).
- Very good knowledge of PostgreSQL database and SQL queries
- Customer service skills
- Computer skills
- Time management